Finding Aid for the Katherine Philips Edson Papers LSC.0235
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence (1913-1932)
  - (1916), 60 pieces
    - Florence Kelley., Results of national election, Charles Evans Hughes, minimum wage and sanitary regulations in industry, conflicting jurisdiction of state commissions, Industrial Welfare Commission, canning industry, Hughes Train. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Lolita van Rensselaer., Introducing Alicia Mosgrove, national election. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hiram Johnson., Edward A. Dickson, Edwin T. Earl, Meyer Lissner. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., National election, Hiram Johnson, federal 8-hour bill, Frances Noel, Woman's Republican League in East, Miss Rankin, women's movement in West, Industrial Welfare Commission, canning industry, California 8-Hour Law, Helen Bary, anti-injunction legislation, sanitary regulations for women and minors, minimum wage. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Lolita van Renssalaer., Details of California's role in national election, Alvin S. Johnson's article in New Republic, William H. Crocker, Chester Rowell at Republican National Convention, Hiram Johnson, Willis Booth, Charles Evans Hughes, Francis V. Keesling, Anne Rhodes, Southern Pacific Railroad and politics, Progressives vs. reactionaries in Republican Party, Meyer Lissner, Edward A. Dickson, Marshall Stimson, Mary S. Gibson, Russ Avery, William D. Stephens, Farnum, Woodrow Wilson and foreign policy, Mexico, William Randolph Hearst, Theodore Roosevelt, Hughes Train, Florence Guggenheim, Democratic Party. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Frances A. Kellor., National election, Miss Kellor's article for Yale Review. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - (1917), 57 pieces
    - Hiram Johnson., Albert Bonnheim's successor on Industrial Welfare Commission, A.B.C. Dohrmann, Y.R. Millar, Meyer Lissner, Thorpe, Cora Woodbridge, Sig Stern, Cameron, Louis Cole. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hiram Johnson., State Senator Arthur H. Breed, proposed constitutional amendment regarding taxation, initiative, and referendum; Los Angeles Times, Lloyd George and British House of Lords, Southern Pacific Railroad. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Charles Johnson Post., Film on women in politics. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Charles Johnson Post., Film. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hiram Johnson., Successor to Albert Bonnheim on Industrial Welfare Commission, Y.R. Millar, Louis H. Cole, R.I. Bentley, Jesse Steinhart, Max Rosenberg, Alexander Goldstein, Chester Rowell, Harris Weinstock, Mrs. James Orr. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alicia Mosgrove., National election, Republican Party: Progressives and reactionaries, Women's League for Service, William D. Stephens, James Rolph, Jr., Francis Heney, Anne Morgan. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hiram Johnson., Industrial Welfare Commission appointment. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Chester Rowell., Robins luncheon, Rowell speaking engagements regarding social health insurance. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Meyer Lissner., Hiram Johnson. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alicia Mosgrove., Hiram Johnson, William D. Stephens, California child labor bill and Publishers Association lobby, Dr. Brougher, Judge Curtis D. Wilbur, Women's Legislative Council and community property bills, Edson family. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Chester Rowell., William D. Stephens appointments to Council for Defense, Mrs. Hearst, Mrs. Cowles, Miss Moore, Edward A. Dickson, Paul Scharrenberg. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - William D. Stephens., 8-hour law for women, World War I, vacancy on Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Chester Rowell., Meyer Lissner, William D. Stephens, Mary S. Gibson, Hiram Johnson, Mrs. Hearst, Hearst newspapers, Mrs. Cowles, Ethel Moore, Industrial Welfare Commission, commission government and World War I. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hiram Johnson., California political affairs, William D. Stephens, A.H. Naftzger, Edward A. Dickson, Martin Madsen, Prendergast. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - William D. Stephens., Industrial Welfare Commission, canning industry and 8-Hour Law. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John S. Macfarland., Community property bill, Women's Legislative Council, minimum wage, contitutionality question, William D. Stephens, McDonald bill, (exempting school children from medical supervision), anti-injunction bill, State Senators Kehoe and Benson. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - William D. Stephens., McDonald bill. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - William D. Stephens., Market bill, Harris Weinstock, State Senators Edward Wolf and William E. Brown, A.E. Boynton, Guggenheim interests. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - William D. Stephens., Vocational education bill, kindergartens for working mothers, moron colony. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Jessica Peixotto., Women's Committee of the National Council for Defense, Marie Obenauer, National League for Women's Service, Mrs. Arthur Kyle, Shelley Tolhurst, minimum wage. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bertha von der Nienburg., Canning industry, striking, Miss Herkner, Miss Lathrop, National Child Labor Law, Mrs. Spannagel's bungling, National League for Women's Service, State Council of Defense, Alice M. Kelley. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., Gompers-Harriman Committee, National League for Women's Service, Marie Obenauer, government contracts and industry, cannery strike, Harris Weinstock, Ralph P. Merritt, Walter Mathewson, Industrial Welfare Commission and minimum wage, Raymond Robins. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hiram Johnson., Robert Hardy recommended for captaincy in Officer's Reserve Corps. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Marie Obenauer., Women employment in firms holding government contracts, Mrs. Spannagle, canning industry, factory workers and farmers and the draft, Council of Defense, discontent with foreigners, Committee on Women in Industry, Shelley Tolhurst, College Federation of Women's Clubs, Myra K. Miller, Mrs. Spinks, National League for Women's Service. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Martin C. Madsen., Richard J. Jose and Industrial Welfare Commission position, Labor Committee of Council of Defense, Harris Weinstock, Moody, William D. Stephens, Chester Rowell, Walter Mathewson. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - (telegram) Carrie C. Catt., Congratulations on suffragists' victory. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Jessica Peixotto. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Marie Obenauer., Maude Wetmore, Labor Secretary William B. Wilson, Commissioner General Anthony Caminetti, Mrs. S. Joseph, Mrs. Spinks, government contracts, garment industry, Kirstein Committee, Felix Frankfurter, Mark Gerstle, duplicate investigations of industry, Industrial Welfare Commission, minimum wage, Immigration and Housing Commission, Mexican farm labor. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hiram Johnson., President's Mediation Committee, Martin Madsen, Felix Frankfurter, Louis Brandeis, Industrial Welfare Commission, canning industry, prison-made garments, John I. Nolan, Senator John Sharp Williams. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - (1918), 26 pieces
    - William D. Stephens., State Council of Defense, Committee on Farm Labor; Mexican and Chinese labor, John P. Irish, Walter Mathewson, survey of labor needs. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Chester Rowell., Coming election, labor survey, George Bell, Martin Madsen, Harris Weinstock, Simon J. Lubin, John Francis Neylan, Dr. John R. Haynes, William D. Stephens, Goldstein, market commissioners' bill, Meyer Lissner, Edward A. Dickson; M. Edgarton, James D. Phelan, and Railroad Commission. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dr. Jessica Peixotto., Labor survey, Women in Industry and Child Welfare departments, canning industry, Industrial Welfare Commission, immigrant labor, garment industry, government contracts, Marie Obenauer, Women's Council of Defense, Children's Bureau, Dr. Adelaide Brown, Dr. Ruud, Miss Stoddart. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Elsinore Crowell., Chester Rowell, Meyer Lissner, Mrs. Crowell's article, Industrial Accident Commission, Immigration and Housing Commission, Blue Sky Commission, Hiram Johnson, California Railroad Commission.; Elsinore Crowell's article on Katherine Philips Edson (with corrections by Katherine Philips Edson, Chester Rowell, and Meyer Lissner): commission government, Herbert Hoover, Hiram Johnson, Massachusetts' pioneering, sketch of Katherine Philips Edson's personality, Industrial Welfare Commission, canning industry, minimum wage, hours and working conditions. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - John S. Macfarland., Chester Rowell's possible candidacy for governorship, Edward A. Dickson, Alexander McCabe, William D. Stephens. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hiram Johnson., Recommending William F. Dunning for government office, Francis Heney, William D. Stephens, Los Angeles Times' attack on commissions, Jaye O. Hayes, Edwin T. Earl, Governor Wallace, George Creel, Josephine Goldmark, Industrial Welfare Commission and minimum wage, Ben F. Schlesinger, canning industry, World War I. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Edward A. Dickson., William D. Stephens and social health insurance, Max Kuhl, Mrs. Grimes, Dr. Rene Bine. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - William D. Stephens., Election campaign, Felix Frankfurter, conference of labor officials in Washington, John P. McLaughlin, Walter Mathewson. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - (telegram) George Bell. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner., Recommending Walter Mathewson for appointment. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Judge Louis W. Myers., Myers' request for recommendation to position on Los Angeles District Court of Appeals. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - (1919), 16 pieces
    - Felix Frankfurter., National Women's Land Army, Densmore and U.S. Employment Service, Ethel P. Howes, garment industry, minimum wage, mercantile industry, new Efficiency and Economy Committee of California state government. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Article on Bolshevism. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Woman suffrage convention in St. Louis, California women and minimum wage, State Federation of Women's Clubs, Hiram Johnson, Woodrow Wilson and women, Prison Special. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., Woman suffrage convention, War Labor Policies Board conference of labor officials, women's work in Washington, D.C., California Republican Party, Florence Collins Porter, Will H. Hays, Hiram Johnson, Republican National Convention, Ruth McCormick, Maude Wetmore, Women's Department. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., Woman suffrage convention, Mary S. Gibson, Meyer Lissner, Mrs. Dean, social health insurance and Christian Scientists, Jessie Russell, Mrs. J.B. Stearns, Industrial Welfare Commission and minimum wage, Association for Civic Betterment, Parent Teacher Association (PTA), Hiram Johnson. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. James Wentz., Women and partisan politics, National League of Women Voters. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Florence Kelley., Sanitary regulations, wages and hours in citrus industry, Mrs. Benjamin Nicoll, minimum wage and apprenticeship periods set up. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Carrie C. Catt., California Federation of Women's Clubs convention, National League of Women Voters, Woman's Party, Clara Burdette, Mrs. Dean, woman suffrage convention, Margaret Dreier Robins, Mrs. Cowles, Mary S. Gibson, Hugh Gibson, Woman's Republican Club. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ralph P. Merritt., Toilers of the World, canning industry strike, Preston McKinney, U.S. government wages for unskilled workers. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chester Rowell., Hiram Johnson and League of Nations, Dr. Adelaide Brown. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - (telegram) Carrie C. Catt., Congratulations. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - William D. Stephens., Replacement on Industrial Welfare Commission for Judge Frank J. Murasky, Ralph P. Merritt. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Carrie C. Catt., American Women's Suffrage Association, National League of Women Voters, Clara Burdette, Mrs. Dean, William D. Stephens. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mary anderson., Wage earners with dependents, Conference of Women Workers of the World. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - (January-September 1920), 47 pieces
    - Republican State Central Committee. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chester Rowell, Meyer Lissner, and Mary S. Gibson., Women's Republican Conference, Republican platform in coming election, Will H. Hays, Mary G. Hay, Governor Wallace, Senator Brundage, Guy Earl, Tom Brown, Raymond Benjamin, minimum wage resolution, Dr. Jessie Russell, Clara Burdette, Hiram Johnson, Herbert Hoover. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mary Smith. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Florence C. Porter., Luncheon for Caroline Severance, campaign. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Meyer Lissner., Chester Rowell; Hiram Johnson, Herbert Hoover, and Republican nomination. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Harriet E. Vittum., Hiram Johnson, Herbert Hoover, General Leonard Wood, coming election, League of Nations. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chester Rowell., National woman suffrage covention in Chicago. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Meyer Lissner., Woman suffrage convention. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chester Rowell., Alexander McCabe. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hiram Johnson, Jr., Mrs. Hiram Johnson. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mayme Ober Peak., Mrs. Peak's article for Collier's, Hiram and Mrs. Johnson. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Harry A. Encell., R.J. Millar, California Manufacturer's Association, Industrial Welfare Commission and minimum wage, Hiram Johnson for president. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Lyons and Raas Glacé Fruit Company and Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Clarence Darrow., Asking support of Hiram Johnson for presidential nomination, Fredericks Bordwell, Phil Stanton, Herbert Hoover's campaign. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Carrie C. Catt. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner., Raymond and Margaret Dreier Robins. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Meyer Lissner., Publicity for Johnson for President luncheon, Mrs. Stephens, Mrs. Weyman, Jean Loughborough of the Examiner, Lavinia G. Timmons, Joseph Timmons, Cornelia Pinchot. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Jean Loughborough., Luncheon, Hearst papers, pro-Hoover group, Mary S. Gibson, Grace Simons, Lavinia Timmons. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lavinia Timmons. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Shelley Tolhurst., Hiram Johnson, League of Nations, and other issues; Cornelia Pinchot, Herbert Hoover and women, Gifford Pinchot, Carrie C. Catt. Florence Kelley, Hoover campaign, Warren Harding, Leonard Wood, Phil Stanton, Walter Leeds, Judge Bordwell, John D. Fredericks. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Margaret Dreier Robins., Asking recommendation for Hiram Johnson against Herbert Hoover. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mrs. L.A. Beebe., 8-Hour Law for women. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Will H. Hays., Invitation to Katherine Philips Edson to meet with National Republican Committee. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Harry M. Daugherty., Republican notification ceremonies for Warren G. Harding, minimum wage and Industrial Welfare Commission, coming campaign. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Warren G. Harding., Urging support for protective labor legislation. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Industrial Welfare Commission and canning industry and minimum wage, Warren G. Harding, campaign, Will H. Hays, Progressive Republicans. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Raymond Benjamin., Speech of Mr. Treftz of Better America Federation, Theodore Roosevelt, Woodrow Wilson, Hiram Johnson, James M. Cox, Frank Tyrell, Warren Harding, election campaign. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ruth McCormick., Elmer Dover, Mrs. Robinson, election campaign, Warren G. Harding and Calvin Coolidge, James M. Cox, National Democratic Convention, League of Nations, William Crocker, Rossiter, Margaret Dreier Robins, Raymond Robins, University of California President Barrows, Hiram Johnson, Better America Federation, Harry Haldeman, Los Angeles Express, Los Angeles Times, Hearst papers, Hoover vs. Johnson, Senator Samuel Shortridge, Senator Kent, Mrs. MacCarter, party platforms on social legislation, Senator Boies Penrose, Harry S. New, Will H. Hays. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mary anderson., California minimum wage. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Ethel Palmer., Requesting letters supporting labor legislation for Republican National Committee. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chester Rowell., Katherine Philips Edson's visit to Republican National Headquarters and Warren and Florence Kling Harding, Medill and Ruth McCormick, Charles Sherrell, League of Nations, Margaret Dreier Robins, Hiram Johnson, Judge Welliver, John I. Nolan, Senator Howard Sutherland, Lasker, Senator William E. Borah, Senator McKinney, labor legislation, Woodrow Wilson administration, Senator Philander C. Knox. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - (telegram) Mrs. Frank Northrup. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Warren G. Harding., Republican platform, federal labor legislation, labor unions, Samuel Gompers. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - (October-December 1920), 50 pieces
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland., Election work personal difficulties. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Charles Hebbard., Washington state campaign activities of Bertha Newland, Mrs. Poindexter. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Horace Kimball., Bertha Newland's activities, Margaret Dreier Robins. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Mrs. Frank Northrup. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland., Margaret Dreier Robins, Charles Hebbard, Mrs. Poindexter. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Charles Hebbard., Mrs. Robins' and Hiram Johnson's itineraries. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Horace Kimball. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Mrs. Julius Louisson. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Hiram Johnson., John L. Day (County Republican Chairman in Oregon) asking for Johnson's endorsement for Senator Robert N. Stanfield. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland., Oregon State Committee and Charles Hebbard of Washington do not desire Miss Newland's help. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Mrs. Manley Fosseen., Asking if Bertha Newland is wanted. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Rosa Lee., Asking what Bertha Newland did to warrant her removal. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Belle Cooley. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Raymond Benjamin., Katherine Philips Edson's campaign activities and expenses, Margaret Dreier Robins, Harriet Vittum Mrs. James Morrisson, Mrs. Manley Fosseen, Mrs. W.W. Remington, Scotti Nortland, Samuel Shortridge, James D. Phelan, Williams. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Charles Neuhausen., Bertha Newland. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Bertha Newland., Neuhausen would like Miss Newland's help. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Mrs. Frank Northrup. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Thomas H. Tongue, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Bertha Newland. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Mrs. D. Perozzi. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Mrs. Julius Louisson., Mrs. Robins' speech topics. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Bertha Newland. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. Sylvain A. Lazard. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Trip with Mrs. Robins through Oregon and Northern California, Warren Harding's prospects in West, Bertha Newland's problems in Washington, Sam Walker, Horace Kimball, Mrs. Poindexter, Florence Kling Harding, ex-Governor Frank R. Gooding of Idaho, Governor Davis, Charles Hebbard, Thomas, Rosa Lee, Good, Johnson element in Republican party, Senator Miles Poindexter, Mrs. Frank Northrup, T.B. Neuhausen, Adah Bush, Will H. Hays, William G. McAdoo, Mrs. Funk, Warren Harding and James Cox, Samuel Shortridge vs. James D. Phelan in California, Robert Stanfield vs. Chamberlain in Oregon, Clara Burdette, Herbert Hoover. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Ruth McCormick. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Adah G. Bush., Bertha Newland. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (telegram) Stanley Allen. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. Shelton Bissell. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. Bissell. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mrs. Aaron Sloss., Club Woman magazine and political advertisements. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Republican Party in California and women and labor, Harding and Coolidge Club, Hoover Club, Pro-League Independents, Mrs. Ray L. Wilbur, Mary S. Gibson, Clara Burdette, Republican State Central Committee, Raymond Benjamin; Oregon, Washington, and Arizona Republican Party and women; Mrs. Frank Northrup, Mrs. Louisson, Mrs. Poindexter, National League of Women Voters, Louis Cole, Bartlett, Mrs. Hume, Warren Harding, Will H. Hays. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Meyer Lissner., Chester Rowell's position on Shipping Board. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cornelia Pinchot., Boies Penrose, Will H. Hays, Gifford Pinchot, California Conference of Social Agencies, Hiram Johnson, Republican election victory, Warren Harding, Republican women and National League of Women Voters, Ruth McCormick. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ruth McCormick., Harriet Taylor Upton, Republican Executive Committee, Medill McCormick, Hiram Johnson, League of Nations, National League of Women Voters, women and Democratic Party, old guard Republican Party in California, Better America Federation, Samuel Shortridge. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - (1921), 59 pieces
    - Dr. George H. Whipple., Edson family. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Helen Power., Asking for information about federal appointments, M.J. Kelley, Key Pittman, Herbert Hoover, Tumulty. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Helen Power., Federal appointments for women, Raymond Benjamin, Mrs. Kleugel, Elizabeth Kinney, Alexander McCabe. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mrs. James Wheat., San Bernardino County women's conference at Redlands. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mrs. James Wheat. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Hiram Johnson., Tax Payers League in California, William D. Stephens, proposed consolidation of Industrial Welfare Commission with other departments, Ben F. Schlesinger, Walter Mathewson, Republican Executive Committee, Frederick Howe, James Davis, Herbert Hoover, Warren Harding's cabinet, Better America Federation and Lincoln Republican Club, Henry Robinson, John Willis Baer, Harry Chandler, Edward A. Dickson, Phil Stanton, Harry M. Haldeman, Harry andrews, Marshall Stimson, Henry Robinson, Frank Devlin's appointment as chairman of the Railroad Commission, Chester Rowell's speech on reactionaries, Argonaut attack on William Stephens. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Clara Burdette., Proposed consolidation of Industrial Welfare Commission, Johnson's administration in California and his Ten Commandments, minimum wage, 8-hour law, child labor law, John Eshleman, canning industry. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - form letter to California club women., California Federated Women's Clubs convention, Industrial Welfare Commission, Hiram Johnson, William D. Stephens. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Hiram Johnson., Harriet Kleugel and appointment on Children's Bureau of Department of Labor, Julia Lathrop, Dr. Adelaide Brown, Harriet Kleugel's election activities, Samuel Shortridge and William D. Stephens, Elmer Dover, Lou Henry Hoover and Herbert Hoover, possible federal appointment for Katherine Philips Edson, Japanese in California, V.S. McClatchy, Meyer Lissner and Shipping Board, Blair, maternity bill. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth Macdonald. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Frances Noel., Sending women to Bryn Mawr for a summer course in industrial leadership, Leah Dobkin. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Shelley Tolhurst., Details on Bryn Mawr summer course arrangements, Leah Dobkin, Anne Guthrie. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mrs. J.F. Sartori. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dora Haynes., Bryn Mawr course, YWCA and Better America Federation. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - B.C. Bemis. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - B.C. Bemis. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson., Mabel Willebrandt's and Clara S. Foltz' candidacy for Assistant U.S. Attorney General, Frank Doherty. (Box 1, Folder 10)